Andrés Felipe Posada Quiroz

Medellín, Colombia · https://linkedin.com/in/aposadadev · +57 3194283920 · andres.posada0919@gmail.com

I am a software engineer with over six years of experience in web development, specializing in JavaScript and frameworks such as Vue JS, React JS, and Node JS. I have participated in diverse projects, improving user interfaces, designing REST APIs, optimizing performance, and developing complete systems. I am passionate about solving complex problems and creating intuitive solutions that enhance the user experience. I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to improve my skills and grow as a professional.

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, SASS, Tailwind, Storybook, VueJS, ReactJS, NuxtJS, React Native y Jest.

Backend: NodeJS (Express, Fastify, Nest), RESTful APIs.

Bases de datos: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Firebase. **Others:** Docker, Docker Compose, Git, agile methodologies.

EXPERIENCE

WeAre Dev SAS Medellín,Colombia

FullStack Developer

Sept 2021-Oct 2024

- I designed and developed from scratch a web platform for sending and receiving remittances, successfully bringing it to production.
- I led the migration of a legacy platform, modernizing the credit card and loans payment online system, and I optimized the generation of debt certificates and bank references.
- I performed maintenance and optimization of a web system for loan requests and management, improving its performance and user experience.

O.S Group Medellín, Colombia

FullStack Developer

Sept 2020-Sept 2021

• I designed and developed a web application for requesting, managing, and paying credits, implementing both the frontend and the APIs in the backend to optimize financial processes and improve the user experience.

PLM Group Medellín, Colombia

FullStack Developer Oct 2019–Sept 2020

• I developed the web application and official website for El Dorado Airport in Bogotá, working on both the frontend and backend to manage multiple user-oriented services. The platform allowed users to check flights, access information about stores and retail stores, complete COVID-19 health surveys, and get other relevant information, both from the website and the mobile app.

Sumimedical Medellín, Colombia

FullStack Developer May 2018–Oct 2019

• I led the design, development, and implementation of healthcare software, participating in all stages, from database architecture, API development, and view design to deployment in production. The platform enabled patient care, medication dispensing, inventory and PQRS management, monitoring of patients' status in

third-party facilities, real-time chat, role and permission management, and administration of a service voucher with prices, optimizing the redirection of patients based on the best available care.

EDUCATION

SMART ACADEMY Medellin, Colombia

English B2 July 2024

INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO METROPOLITANO Medellin, Colombia

System Engineer July 2022

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

• Spanish Native and English Intermediate.